# Curriculum Vitae



Chrétien van Veldhuizen Senior FrontEnd Developer Residence Bodegraven



# Introduction

A bridge between man and machine, that's me! As a FrontEnd developer with a focus on Angular, TypeScript, process optimization, AWS and communication, I ensure the perfect user experience. Delivering high quality code in for example TypeScript and Angular gives me energy. I am a real team player who can easily communicate with other areas of expertise. From meetup organizer to software engineer, I am the bridge between man and machine.

During my last project I used my organizational and technical skills to guide Aegon in the cloud transition. For example, by building a cost dashboard. Characteristic of me is that I am proactive and not afraid to ask questions. In practice, for example, I can explain technology to the business in a comprehensible manner.

I want to develop myself broadly in the technical field. For example, I have obtained AWS certifications. This allows me to ask critical questions and ensure quality for the entire process, instead of just my code. I get energy from sharing knowledge and getting to know new people. I also organize the necessary meetups within Sogeti to promote knowledge sharing within Front-end. I am currently specializing in software development. I mainly focus on JavaScript/TypeScript aspects of frontend development.

In my spare time I enjoy strategy and socializing. I am a fanatic follower of Formula 1, I like to play board games and games. In addition, I love to exercise, so that I can go for it again with full energy.

# **Expertise**

- JSON
- JavaScript
- HTML5
- GIT
- Front-end web development
- DevOps
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS3)
- Azure DevOps Services
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Unit testing

- TypeScript
- Python
- Angular
- Bootstrap





# Work experience & education

# **Recent Experience**

09/2020 -  $03/2022\,$  AEGON Nederland N.V.

05/2020 - 08/2020 InnoSportLab de Tongelreep

12/2019 - 06/2020 Sogeti Nederland B.V. 11/2019 - present Sogeti Nederland B.V.

# **Education**

- HBO Bachelor: Communication & Multimedia Design
- OHIO University Business Course
- TMAP: Quality for cross-functional teams
- Course: The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology: Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: Angular
- Course: The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology: Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4

# **Certificates**

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- TMap: Quality for cross-functional teams
- Professional Scrum Master (PSM1)

# Languages

- Engels
- Dutch

# **Trainings**

- DevOps
- Didaktische vaardigheden

Function: Cloud/DevOps Engineer
Client: AEGON Nederland N.V.
Period: September 2020 - March 2022

# **Description**

Deployed at the most innovative part of Aegon, namely Cloud and support, I worked within the Cloud platform management (CPM) team as a Cloud/DevOps engineer. Aegon is an international insurance and pension company. Aegon is in the midst of a cloud transition. I was responsible for building cloud solutions, preparing for migrations and developing a cost dashboard.

During the development of the Aegon cloud cost dashboard, I had a leading role. This was because I combined my frontend knowledge with AWS knowledge. Thanks to my organizational skills, I was able to convert the business requirements into technology. For example, I built the dashboard with Python, TypeScript, AWS and Azure DevOps together with the CPM team. I took the product owners, product managers and financial managers with me and guided them during the development. In addition to the cost dashboard, I contributed to documentation of the technology in the form of cloud audits. I have further developed the services that CPM provides to Aegon teams, such as Hawkeye (a security tool), Azure DevOps pipelines, etc. During the absence of our scrum master, I fulfilled this role in a structured and clear manner.

Due to my broad knowledge, I have been able to develop both the software technical side and the "DevOps" mentality in the Aegon value streams. Aegon uses the AWS cost dashboard on a daily basis to calculate costs in combination with. keep an eye on budgets. "Without the cost dashboard, teams have no insight into the Aegon costs for using AWS."

#### **Expertise**

Agile/Scrum, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Azure DevOps Services, CI / CD, DevOps, GIT, Postman API development environment, Python, TypeScript



Function: FrontEnd developer

Client: InnoSportLab de Tongelreep

Period: May 2020 - August 2020

#### **Description**

For InnoSportLab de Tongelreep I worked on "The smart swimming sensor app". This innovation project was set up with a team of Sogeti colleagues. The purpose of the application is to analyse swimmers' training and forward this data to the swimmer.

I was responsible for the Frontend of the application. Because of my knowledge of Angular, I quickly saw the similarities in Ionic. For example, I have the connection with the backend by means of REST APIs, form fields and the login function built. I did this through AWS Cognito and Ionic. The project had to be built from scratch. My approach has been decisive for the development of the project. For example, I organized a consultation with the designer, backend developer and product owner to determine the course of the application. I worked closely with the backend developer because of the short duration of this innovation project. This is where my communication and technical skills came in handy. Functioning as a bridge between man and machine has once again been my strength in this project.

The result of my activities has ensured that many technical defects have been resolved in advance. Working in a team and the rapid switching between techniques has ensured that the application is a success and InnoSportlab de Tongelreep is currently developing the application further.

## **Expertise**

Agile/Scrum, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Front-end development, HTML, Ionic, JSON, Mobile development, TypeScript

Function: FrontEnd Developer
Client: Sogeti Nederland B.V.
Period: December 2019 - June 2020

# **Description**

SoPickMeUp is a carpool web app that makes it possible for Sogetists to ride together to events and training. This makes the journey more fun, more efficient, and more environmentally conscious. In a team of developers and designers I acted as frontend developer and scrum master. This with CSR, security and AVG always in mind.

I was responsible for the connection of the backend, built components and services and implemented designs. All this in Angular 8 in combination with bootstrap and REST APIs. For example, I made forms, the login function, and services in TypeScript. In this project I had short lines with the designer and back-ender and we switched gears quickly and efficiently. As a result, impactful design choices are made or not.

As a scrum master I was responsible as a facilitator, communication point and source of information for the team. In this role I acted transparently and directly. For example, I have set up a structure to communicate to the stakeholders in a short and clear manner. This resulted in a project that was picked up and noticed by all layers within Sogeti. Facets such as GDPR, CSR and security have come to play a major role as the project has grown.

During this project I gained knowledge of both the business side and the technical side of projects. The result of this is that SoPickMeUp is still a long way from being developed. Everyone who used SoPickMeUp became very enthusiastic because it is more environmentally conscious, efficient and more fun to go to events and training sessions together.

#### **Expertise**

Angular, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Front-end development, GIT, Bootstrap HTML, REST, TypeScript, Unit testing



Function: Software Engineer
Client: Sogeti Nederland B.V.
Period: November 2019 - present

#### **Description**

As a software engineer at Sogeti I started a business course at OHIO University. For three weeks, high performance teams worked on the development of three concepts. Every week the team members and their roles changed, and a concept had to be presented. I acted as a software engineer and scrum master. I started working in a structured and transparent way. With the Explainable AI concept, I and my team won the final presentations!

Within the Interaction community I fulfil my role as Frontend developer by working with technology and people. I am not afraid to share my opinion or ask questions. I love the continuous development with courses and practical experience. I also like to bring this back to the customer, for example through innovation sprints and contributing to the developer community.

I am active in the frontend core team. Within the frontend core team, I am involved in knowledge sharing. I love organizing and hosting the Frontend Lightning talks and organizing the interaction Friday meetups. I am currently immersing myself in software development. I mainly focus on JavaScript/TypeScript aspects of frontend development.

## **Expertise**

Agile/Scrum, Angular, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Front-end development, GIT, HTML, Jasmine, JavaScript, JSON, TypeScript

Function: UX/UI/Service Designer
Client: Icemobile Agency B.V.
Period: February 2019 - May 2019

#### **Description**

Icemobile Agency is an international company specialized in app development for supermarkets all over the world. I did a complete redesign of the mobile app here for DEEN supermarkets. In this project I was responsible for all activities. From involving the stakeholders in the project to justifying all design choices. Examples of tasks are researching the target group, generating concepts, designing, and communicating with the development team. I have broad professional knowledge. For example, when setting up and performing user tests, I took accessibility into account. Through the results of the design and research, Icemobile has gained insight into DEEN Supermarkets' customers.

The Lead UX (David Brandeau, German) was so impressed with my attitude and work that I gave a presentation to the entire development team. This resulted in the development team talking more about the goal of the development work. David has said the following about me: ""I think Chrétien is a smart, talented, curious, hard-working, and very nice guy. He's only 20 years old so I expect him to develop a lot over the next coming years"

# **Expertise**

Interaction Design, (Design) patterns, Presentation techniques, Prototyping, User-Centered Design, Usability, Usability testing, Accessibility



Function: **UX Consultant & Researcher** 

Client: Stichting Studielink

Period: November 2018 - February 2019

# **Description**

Stichting Studielink takes care of the registration process for universities of applied sciences in the Netherlands. I gave advice with a team in the field of User Experience and Frontend development. During the research I was responsible for the user flow, WCAG (accessibility) and usability of the form. I tackled this in a structured way by first orienting myself. The target group was mapped out in an experience map by means of personas and in-depth interviews. The advice has been formed based on the results delivered, discussions with stakeholders and Studielink. During the final presentation to the entire team, everyone became enthusiastic. The advice has been included in the next Studielink sprints.

#### **Expertise**

Agile/Scrum, Front-end development, Interaction Design, Presentation techniques, Usability testing, Accessibility

Function: **UX Consultant & Researcher** 

Client: Glasnet

Period: august 2018 - october 2018

# **Description**

The team, where I worked as a UX researcher, received the following question from Glasnet: "How can the user experience be improved during the three-month preparation period for fibber optic cables." Glasnet is an internet provider that focuses on fibber optics and its construction. I was responsible for the user research. Meetings with stakeholders are organized every week to be able to take steps quickly. I have formulated my advice using techniques such as experience maps and interviews. I have worked in a structured manner. For example, by clearly giving useful and short briefings to my team beforehand and afterwards. Within three months, the team delivered three concepts. These concepts have focused on user experience, communication, and conversion. Glasnet was impressed by the dedication and commitment of the team and the results delivered. With this advice, the frontend team was able to adjust the flow of the website.

# **Expertise**

Agile/Scrum, Communication Techniques (-plan, -training, etc.), Interaction Design, Presentation techniques, Prototyping, Usability

Function: FrontEnd developer/All Round Designer

Client: **IQ Leads B.V.** 

Period: september 2017 - february 2018

#### **Description**

I have worked at IQ Leads as a frontend developer and all round designer. IQ Leads is a full stack ICT company. Within the team of developers, I started communication processes with design. I also helped develop a design system. I was responsible for logos, website designs and user research. During this period, I designed three complete websites. I also mapped out the design process from the customer to the backend. This allows the process to be performed more efficiently. An example of this is the design system. By collecting information from each expertise in a structured and respectful way, I was able to build a design system. This resulted in improved designs and development speed. IQ Leads has implemented this system in their daily work. My strength has been in picking up new material quickly, creating communication and respect between the expertise's.

#### **Expertise**

Agile/Scrum, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Front-end development, HTML, (Design) patterns, User-Centered Design, Accessibility, WordPress